Guide to the Raymond Clark Hitchings papers, 1808-1959
Hitchings, Raymond Clark papers, 1808-1959
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Raymond Clark Hitchings papers, 1808-1959, 1870-1945 (bulk)
2580
Raymond Clark Hitchings, 1892-
4 cubic ft.
Accounts, correspondence, financial and legal records, speeches, genealogical information, farm records, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Accounts, correspondence, and financial and legal records relating to Hitchings's various positions as an officer and employee of the Co-operative Grange League Federation Exchange (ca. 1920-1928) and as a consultant and officer in various agricultural agencies; also, other personal and family papers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Agricultural consultant.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Accounts, correspondence, and financial and legal records relating to Hitchings's various positions as an officer and employee of the Co-operative Grange League Federation Exchange (ca. 1920-1928) and as a consultant and officer in various agricultural agencies; also, records (1930-1935) relating to Hitchings's tenure as a member and as president of the Board of Education of Onondaga Centralized School District #1, his correspondence with the Americanization League of Syracuse and Onondaga County (ca. 1923-1927), and speeches he gave before farm groups. Hitchings family papers include an autobiographical sketch; an unpublished manuscript by his brother, Harold Ramsdell Hitchings; a diary (1884) of his father, Grant G. Hitchings; genealogical information; and other items relating to the family farm at South Onondaga, New York, including general farm and orchard accounts (41 vols., 1808-1926), labor reports (2 vols., 1910-1911), and records of a sod mulch and cultivated orchard experiment (3 vols., 1904-1914).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hitchings, Raymond Clark, 1892-; Hitchings family.; Hitchings, Grant G.; Hitchings, Harold Ramsdell.; Americanization League of Syracuse and Onondaga County.; Cooperative Grange League Federation Exchange.; Onondaga Centralized School District #1.
Subjects:
Agriculture--New York (State); Farms.; Mulching.; Orchards--New York (State); Farmers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Accounts.; Autobiographies.; Diaries.; Genealogies.; Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Professional papers
  - Co-operative Grange League Federation Exchange
    - Ms. History of the Establishment of the Co-operative Grange League Federation Exchange, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes of the Meetings of the Board of Directors of the C.G.L.F.E. (incomplete carbons), 1920-1926 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee of the C.G.L.F.E., Inc. (incomplete carbons), 1920-1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes of the Department Head and Program Department Head Conferences (carbons), July 26-28, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re: the C.F.L.F.E. including memo re: Hitchings' dual responsibilities as warehouse manager and secretary-treasurer, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re: C.G.L.F.E., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re: C.G.L.F.E., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re: the C.G.L.F.E., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re: the C.G.L.F.E. including proposed corporation insurance on the life of Mr. H.E. Babcock, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re: the C.G.L.F.E., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re: the C.G.L.F.E., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence re: the C.G.L.F.E. including H.E. Babcock's letter of resignation, 1932, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Fiscal papers, largely balance sheets and statements re: the C.G.L.F.E. and Producers' Warehouse & Elevator Company, 1921-1927 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
    - Miscellaneous legal papers re: C.G.L.F.E., Sept. 2, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous fiscal records re: C.G.L.F.E., 1932, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous inventories and statistical data re: the C.G.L.F.E., 1922-1926 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous C.G.L.F.E. and Producers' Warehouse and Elevator Company periodicals, including incomplete runs of the Warehouse Managers Weekly Newsletter and the G.L.F. Stockholder, 1920-1930 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous circulars re: the C.G.L.F.E. including "Some Facts about the C.G.L.F.E.", 1920-1930, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Government career (miscellaneous agencies)
    - Correspondence and related items re: the Surplus Marketing Administration, U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Records of Procurement Seeds from America (U.S. & Canada) through the British Food Mission for the Ministry of Agriculture" (oversize), 1941-1947 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence and related papers re: seed shipments, Surplus Marketing Administration, U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Marshall Plan Commodities shipped to Europe in 1947 (looseleaf notebook), 1947 (Box 3)
    - Notebook containing charge-out cards and code list (1948) of Economic Cooperation Administration (notebook), 1948 (Box 3)
    - Statistics on Roumanian corn, Surplus Marketing Administration, U.S. Department of Agriculture, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and related items re: rice exports, Office of Price Stabilization, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous records, 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Mimeographed material re: the International Cooperation Administration, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - Miscellaneous papers re: the International Farm Youth Exchange, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, notes, and mimeograph circulars re: the 1959 National Farm Union's Farm Training Program at Denver (looseleaf ring binder), 1959 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous grain records (oversize record book without cover), 1948-1949 (Box 3)
- Series II. Personal, civic, and social papers
  - Personal
    - R.C. Hitchings, "My Duties for the Past 35 Years" (typescript) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - South Onondaga Central School District and Centralized School District #1
    - Miscellaneous papers re: the Suth Onondaga Central School District and the Centralized School District #1, including minutes, legal and fiscal records, 1930-1934 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Americanization League of Syracuse and Onondaga County
    - Reports and correspondence re: the American League of Syracuse and Onondaga County, 1921-1927 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous speeches
    - 1. Who is Fenced In, the Dairyman or the Herd?", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 2. "Fruit Growing as a Business Today", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 3. Untitled, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Series III. Hitchings family papers
  - Genealogical records
    - Genealogical records re: the Hitchings Family, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous family papers
    - Bonds, 1871-1929 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Deeds, 1865-1926 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Mortgages, 1853-1931 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Debate minutes: "Resolved, that the East offers better inducement to young men than the West", 1887 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Harold R. Hitchings: "Sod Mulch Orchard Management" (ms. book), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Diary of Grant G. Hitchings (leather covered diary), Jan. 1-Dec. 31, 1884 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Legal papers re: right of way on the Hitchings Farm, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Series IV. Hitchings family farm records
  - Farm accounts
    - Hitchings Account Book, John Hitchings property, Dec. 1, 1808-Apr. 8, 1872 (Box 8)
    - Farm Accounts, Labor Records and notes (day book), 1860-1867 (Box 8)
    - Personal family accounts (day book), 1877 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1870-1878 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1878-1883 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1884 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1886 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1888 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1889 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1890 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1891-1892 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1895-1896 (Box 7)
    - Farm inventory and accounts (day book), 1897 (Box 7)
    - Inventory, statement, and farm accounts (day book), 1899-1900 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1903 (Box 7)
    - Grant G. Hitchings' inventory, statements, accounts (miscellaneous record book), 1901-1902 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1903-1904 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1904 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1905 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1906 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1907 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1908 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1909 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1910 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1911 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1912 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1913 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts, inventory, and statements (day book), 1914 (Box 7)
    - Farm inventory and accounts (day book), 1915 (Box 7)
    - Farm inventory and accounts (day book), 1916 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous accounts and inventory (bound book), 1917 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1918 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous accounts, inventory (bound book), 1919-1921 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1920 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1921 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1922 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1923 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1924 (Box 7)
    - Farm accounts (day book), 1925 (Box 7)
    - "Account of operation and sales of fruit orchard owned by W.T. White which consist of 14 A sold to him in 1909 by G.G. Hitchings", 1910 (Box 7)
    - Grocery accounts (day book), 1924 (Box 7)
  - Labor reports
    - United States Department of Agriculture in Farm Management Investigations ..., Regular Worker's Daily Time Sheet, 1910 (Box 8)
    - United States Department of Agriculture, Proprietors or Superintendents Daily Labor Report (bound book), 1911 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Two scrapbooks of farm clippings, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sod mulch and cultivated orchards experiment
    - Records, Sod mulch and cultivated orchards experiment with Geneva Agricultural Station, Plot A (record book), 1904-1914 (Box 8)
    - Records, Sod mulch and cultivated orchards experiment with Geneva Agricultural Station, Plot B (record book), 1904-1914 (Box 8)
    - Records, Sod mulch and cultivated orchards experiment with Geneva Agricultural Station, Plot C (record book), 1904-1914 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous records
    - Farm records - Record for United States Department of Agriculture re: daily operations and cost for apple orchards, oats and barley, corn, berries, wheat (work record), 1912-1913 (Box 8)
    - "Orchards as planted from 1885 to 1930 on page 20" (journal), 1885-1930 (Box 8)
    - Farm records, primarily re: daily operation and labor costs (record book), 1914 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, apple basket labels, etc., n.d. (Box 8)
    - Map of farm of Grant G. Hitchings, Syracuse, New York, 1910
    - Part of farm lot No. 221 Onondaga Reservation, Town of Onondaga, New York (map), n.d.
    - Farm plan, G.G. Hitchings, Syracuse, New York (map), n.d.
    - Highway survey, Mar. 30, 1930 (map), 1930